<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ProHits-viz</title>
    <description>News and tutorials on visualizing data at ProHits-viz.</description>
    <link>https://prohits-viz.org/news</link>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 09:39:40 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>2.0 alpha test begins</title>
      <description>Learn about the first stage of testing for the new ProHits-viz interface.</description>
      <link>https://prohits-viz.org/news/2.0-alpha-test-begins</link>
      <guid>https://prohits-viz.org/news/2.0-alpha-test-begins</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>
        &lt;p&gt;The alpha test for the 2.0 version of ProHits-viz has begun. It can be accessed at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org&quot;&gt;prohits-viz.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are currently testing only the dot plot tool with its associated interactive viewer. Some features from the previous version of the interactive viewer have not yet been implemented, including domain and network analysis, as well as image archiving.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To make our tools more approachable for those outside the interaction proteomics community, all bait and prey nomenclature has (or will be) converted to &quot;condition&quot; and &quot;readout&quot;. This will affect file naming, so what would previously have been called bait-bait.svg will now be condition-condition.svg.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New features include the ability to save interactive sessions to a file or the browser, navigate large images using the new &quot;minimap&quot; feature, sort conditions by readout abundance either by condition or for one condition relative to another (fold-change), as well as several new ways of selecting conditions/readouts for analysis and image customization. You can try out the new features with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org/visualization/samplefile/dotplot&quot;&gt;example dataset&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have a very large image and use the new sorting options, this may be slow. This will be addressed in a future update.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to provide feedback, report bugs or request new features, please use GitHub. If your issue has already been created on GitHub by someone else, you do not need to do anything unless you would like to provide additional comments or context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create an account on GitHub: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com&quot;&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Skip the tutorial (unless you plan on coding)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/knightjdr/prohits-viz-client/issues&quot;&gt;https://github.com/knightjdr/prohits-viz-client/issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click on the green &quot;New issue&quot; button to create a new issue and describe the issue, bug or feature.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Alternatively, browse and comment on issues created by others&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GIX browser extension released</title>
      <description>Quickly retreive gene information at ProHits-viz using the GIX browser extension.</description>
      <link>https://prohits-viz.org/news/GIX-browser-extension-released</link>
      <guid>https://prohits-viz.org/news/GIX-browser-extension-released</guid>
      <pubDate>Friday, 2 Aug 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>
        &lt;p&gt;GIX (Gene Information eXtension) is a browser extension we developed that can retrieve gene information directly on any website. It is a great companion tool for ProHits-viz as it allows you to quickly retrieve gene information when browsing images on the interactive viewer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about it at &lt;a href=&quot;https://gene-info.org&quot;&gt;gene-info.org&lt;/a&gt; and read our article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-019-0477-9&quot;&gt;Nature Methods&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.0 beta test of dot plot and correlation tools</title>
      <description>Learn about the next stage of testing for the new ProHits-viz interface.</description>
      <link>https://prohits-viz.org/news/2.0-beta-test-of-dot-plot-and-correlation-tools</link>
      <guid>https://prohits-viz.org/news/2.0-beta-test-of-dot-plot-and-correlation-tools</guid>
      <pubDate>Friday, 6 Mar 2020 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>
        &lt;p&gt;The beta test for the 2.0 version of ProHits-viz has begun. It can be accessed at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org&quot;&gt;prohits-viz.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are currently testing the correlation and dot plot tools with their associated interactive viewer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the features mentioned in the alpha test and further bug fixes, you can now filter interactive images by conditions (e.g. baits) to limit the readouts (e.g. preys) displayed on the image. This is particular useful when combined with sorting to provide a more focused look at two conditions. You can also open as many snapshots and analyses of your image as you would like. You can try out the new features with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org/visualization/samplefile/dotplot&quot;&gt;example dataset&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to provide feedback, report bugs or request new features, please use GitHub. If your issue has already been created on GitHub by someone else, you do not need to do anything unless you would like to provide additional comments or context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create an account on GitHub: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com&quot;&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Skip the tutorial (unless you plan on coding)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/knightjdr/prohits-viz-client/issues&quot;&gt;https://github.com/knightjdr/prohits-viz-client/issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click on the green &quot;New issue&quot; button to create a new issue and describe the issue, bug or feature.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Alternatively, browse and comment on issues created by others&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.0 beta test of scatter plot tools</title>
      <description>Scatter plot analysis, with a new interactive viewer, is now live.</description>
      <link>https://prohits-viz.org/news/2.0-beta-test-of-scatter-plot-tools</link>
      <guid>https://prohits-viz.org/news/2.0-beta-test-of-scatter-plot-tools</guid>
      <pubDate>Wednesday, 20 Jan 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>
        &lt;p&gt;Support for scatter plot analysis, including condition-condition analysis (formerly called bait-bait) and readout specificity has been added to ProHits-viz 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These tools come with an updated interactive viewer that allows for customization of the colour and size of points, addition of fold-change lines, toggling between linear and log axes, and selection of points for analysis, such as GO enrichment. You can try out the new features with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org/visualization/samplefile/specificity&quot;&gt;example dataset&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to provide feedback, report bugs or request new features, please use GitHub. If your issue has already been created on GitHub by someone else, you do not need to do anything unless you would like to provide additional comments or context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create an account on GitHub: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com&quot;&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Skip the tutorial (unless you plan on coding)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/knightjdr/prohits-viz-client/issues&quot;&gt;https://github.com/knightjdr/prohits-viz-client/issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click on the green &quot;New issue&quot; button to create a new issue and describe the issue, bug or feature.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Alternatively, browse and comment on issues created by others&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New tool for single condition visualization</title>
      <description>The SCV tool for visualizing data on a single condition (e.g. bait, experiment) is now available.</description>
      <link>https://prohits-viz.org/news/New-tool-for-single-condition-visualization</link>
      <guid>https://prohits-viz.org/news/New-tool-for-single-condition-visualization</guid>
      <pubDate>Thursday, 25 February 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>
        &lt;p&gt;There is a new tool for visualizing data on a single condition (for example a bait in a protein-protein interaction data set). It will display significant readouts in a circular heat map format, with the option to display multiple columns from the input file.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The image can be supplemented with either protein or RNA expression data from a range of cell lines and tissues. For protein-protein interaction data, the image can also be sorted between known and novel interactions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can try out the new tool with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org/visualization/samplefile/circheatmap&quot;&gt;example dataset&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new home</title>
      <description>ProHits-viz has officially moved from its old home.</description>
      <link>https://prohits-viz.org/news/A-new-home</link>
      <guid>https://prohits-viz.org/news/A-new-home</guid>
      <pubDate>Monday, 19 July 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>
        &lt;p&gt;July 18, 2021 was the last day of official support for our old ProHits-viz site hosted at prohits-viz.lunenfeld.ca. Over the course of its four years of existence, it performed over 75 000 analysis and visualization tasks. While it is still used extensively by the community, we felt it was in need of a redesign that would allow us to more easily add new tools and interactive features going forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org&quot;&gt;ProHits-viz.org&lt;/a&gt; is the new redesigned home of ProHits-viz. This new site has an overhauled interface, with extensive online help and video tutorials to aid when you get stuck. It also comes with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org/help/analysis/scv&quot;&gt;brand new tool&lt;/a&gt; for visualizing multiple output metrics from a single experimental condition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is plenty of online help at &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org/help&quot;&gt;prohits-viz.org/help&lt;/a&gt; and a number of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCGR-0ixL4z526JUVQU8P4xQ/playlists&quot;&gt;videos&lt;/a&gt; that demonstrate how to use the new interactive viewers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have questions that are not covered by the help, you can contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:contact@prohits-viz.org&quot;&gt;contact@prohits-viz.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A final note on the old site: any images that were archived there will still be accessible, but all other links will redirect to the new site.&lt;/p&gt;
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support for data from CRISPR workflows</title>
      <description>Data produced by several CRISPR screen analysis tools are now explicitly supported at ProHits-viz.</description>
      <link>https://prohits-viz.org/news/Support-for-data-from-CRISPR-workflows</link>
      <guid>https://prohits-viz.org/news/Support-for-data-from-CRISPR-workflows</guid>
      <pubDate>Wednesday, 6 October 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>
        &lt;p&gt;ProHits-viz was initially designed for the visualization of protein-protein interaction data, but it has always been able to visualize any tabular data that conforms to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org/help/analysis/input-file&quot;&gt;generic input format&lt;/a&gt;. This format requires four parameters for each data point:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;the condition/experiment it belongs to&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the readout being quantified, usually a gene or protein name&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the value to be visualized, typically some sort of abundance metric&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;a score indicating the significance of the value being visualized&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many common proteomic and genomic experiments will generate data consistent with this format, or can be easily converted to it, and can thus benefit from the visualization tools we provide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To date, we have only provided explicit support for the output from two protein-protein interaction analysis tools: 1) SAINT and 2) CRAPome/REPRINT. Data output from other tools, whether from protein-protein interaction studies or some other experiment type, have required conversion by the user to conform with our input format.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are aiming to provide more direct support for the outputs from various analysis pipelines, allowing seamless integration with ProHits-viz, as we seek to make it as simple as possible for users to benefit from our tools. To this end, we have now added explicit support for the visualization of data output from common analysis tools that handle CRISPR experiments. These include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcbioinformatics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12859-016-1015-8&quot;&gt;BAGEL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://genomemedicine.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13073-019-0665-3&quot;&gt;drugZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://genomebiology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13059-014-0554-4&quot;&gt;MAGeCK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.asm.org/doi/10.1128/MCB.00302-17&quot;&gt;RANKS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The metric to visualize from these tools typically takes both positive and negative values, for example a Z-score or log&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; fold change. Previously we required the &amp;ldquo;abundance&amp;rdquo; value to be visualized to only take non-negative values, but all of our tools have now been updated to support negative values as well. In some cases these values get treated as absolute/positive values, for example when calculating the dot size ratio on dot plots: a dot of -10 and +10 will be the same size; or when applying filters: a filter of 1 will now filter anything between -1 and 1, rather than just from 0 to 1. Otherwise visualization should be intuitive and as expected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first step in using CRISPR data at ProHits-viz is to go to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org/utilities&quot;&gt;utilities page&lt;/a&gt; and select the files you would like to analyze. You can select as many files as you would like. Then select the option &amp;ldquo;Convert output from a CRISPR analysis tool to a ProHits-viz compatible format&amp;rdquo; and the tool that produced the files. Hitting submit will return a single file containing all of the input analyses formatted for ProHits-viz. It is important to note that BAGEL, drugZ and RANKS analyze a single experiment at a time, and so if you wish to compare the results from multiple experiments, you must select all of the relevant files at the input stage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the conversion complete, you can head to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org/analysis&quot;&gt;analysis page&lt;/a&gt;, input the converted file and file type, and ProHits-viz will automatically select suitable options from here onwards for any type of analysis you would like to perform.&lt;/p&gt;
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
