<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ProHits-viz</title>
    <description>News and tutorials on visualizing data at ProHits-viz.</description>
    <link>https://prohits-viz.org/news</link>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 16:57:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>2.0 alpha test begins</title>
      <description>Learn about the first stage of testing for the new ProHits-viz interface.</description>
      <link>https://prohits-viz.org/news/2.0-alpha-test-begins</link>
      <guid>https://prohits-viz.org/news/2.0-alpha-test-begins</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>
        &lt;p&gt;The alpha test for the 2.0 version of ProHits-viz has begun. It can be accessed at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org&quot;&gt;prohits-viz.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are currently testing only the dot plot tool with its associated interactive viewer. Some features from the previous version of the interactive viewer have not yet been implemented, including domain and network analysis, as well as image archiving.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To make our tools more approachable for those outside the interaction proteomics community, all bait and prey nomenclature has (or will be) converted to &quot;condition&quot; and &quot;readout&quot;. This will affect file naming, so what would previously have been called bait-bait.svg will now be condition-condition.svg.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New features include the ability to save interactive sessions to a file or the browser, navigate large images using the new &quot;minimap&quot; feature, sort conditions by readout abundance either by condition or for one condition relative to another (fold-change), as well as several new ways of selecting conditions/readouts for analysis and image customization. You can try out the new features with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org/visualization/samplefile/dotplot&quot;&gt;example dataset&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have a very large image and use the new sorting options, this may be slow. This will be addressed in a future update.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to provide feedback, report bugs or request new features, please use GitHub. If your issue has already been created on GitHub by someone else, you do not need to do anything unless you would like to provide additional comments or context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create an account on GitHub: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com&quot;&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Skip the tutorial (unless you plan on coding)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/knightjdr/prohits-viz-client/issues&quot;&gt;https://github.com/knightjdr/prohits-viz-client/issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click on the green &quot;New issue&quot; button to create a new issue and describe the issue, bug or feature.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Alternatively, browse and comment on issues created by others&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GIX browser extension released</title>
      <description>Quickly retreive gene information at ProHits-viz using the GIX browser extension.</description>
      <link>https://prohits-viz.org/news/GIX-browser-extension-released</link>
      <guid>https://prohits-viz.org/news/GIX-browser-extension-released</guid>
      <pubDate>Friday, 2 Aug 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>
        &lt;p&gt;GIX (Gene Information eXtension) is a browser extension we developed that can retrieve gene information directly on any website. It is a great companion tool for ProHits-viz as it allows you to quickly retrieve gene information when browsing images on the interactive viewer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about it at &lt;a href=&quot;https://gene-info.org&quot;&gt;gene-info.org&lt;/a&gt; and read our article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-019-0477-9&quot;&gt;Nature Methods&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.0 beta test of dot plot and correlation tools</title>
      <description>Learn about the next stage of testing for the new ProHits-viz interface.</description>
      <link>https://prohits-viz.org/news/2.0-beta-test-of-dot-plot-and-correlation-tools</link>
      <guid>https://prohits-viz.org/news/2.0-beta-test-of-dot-plot-and-correlation-tools</guid>
      <pubDate>Friday, 6 Mar 2020 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>
        &lt;p&gt;The beta test for the 2.0 version of ProHits-viz has begun. It can be accessed at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org&quot;&gt;prohits-viz.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are currently testing the correlation and dot plot tools with their associated interactive viewer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the features mentioned in the alpha test and further bug fixes, you can now filter interactive images by conditions (e.g. baits) to limit the readouts (e.g. preys) displayed on the image. This is particular useful when combined with sorting to provide a more focused look at two conditions. You can also open as many snapshots and analyses of your image as you would like. You can try out the new features with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org/visualization/samplefile/dotplot&quot;&gt;example dataset&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to provide feedback, report bugs or request new features, please use GitHub. If your issue has already been created on GitHub by someone else, you do not need to do anything unless you would like to provide additional comments or context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create an account on GitHub: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com&quot;&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Skip the tutorial (unless you plan on coding)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/knightjdr/prohits-viz-client/issues&quot;&gt;https://github.com/knightjdr/prohits-viz-client/issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click on the green &quot;New issue&quot; button to create a new issue and describe the issue, bug or feature.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Alternatively, browse and comment on issues created by others&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.0 beta test of scatter plot tools</title>
      <description>Scatter plot analysis, with a new interactive viewer, is now live.</description>
      <link>https://prohits-viz.org/news/2.0-beta-test-of-scatter-plot-tools</link>
      <guid>https://prohits-viz.org/news/2.0-beta-test-of-scatter-plot-tools</guid>
      <pubDate>Wednesday, 20 Jan 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>
        &lt;p&gt;Support for scatter plot analysis, including condition-condition analysis (formerly called bait-bait) and readout specificity has been added to ProHits-viz 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These tools come with an updated interactive viewer that allows for customization of the colour and size of points, addition of fold-change lines, toggling between linear and log axes, and selection of points for analysis, such as GO enrichment. You can try out the new features with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://prohits-viz.org/visualization/samplefile/specificity&quot;&gt;example dataset&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to provide feedback, report bugs or request new features, please use GitHub. If your issue has already been created on GitHub by someone else, you do not need to do anything unless you would like to provide additional comments or context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create an account on GitHub: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com&quot;&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Skip the tutorial (unless you plan on coding)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/knightjdr/prohits-viz-client/issues&quot;&gt;https://github.com/knightjdr/prohits-viz-client/issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click on the green &quot;New issue&quot; button to create a new issue and describe the issue, bug or feature.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Alternatively, browse and comment on issues created by others&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
